“创始吸血鬼”前情提要
WOMAN:
Previously on The Originals.
如果我们不能联手合作
If we can't create
some sort of community,
那还有什么意义？
then what's the point?
不如杀掉彼此早点了事
Kill each other
and get it all over with.
如果你我都不能和平相处
MAN:
If there is no peace between us,
那你怎么能指望其他人跟随呢？
then how can you expect others
to follow suit?
这个城市的居民不会遵守这个协定的
KLAUS: The city's inhabitants
will not adhere to this agreement.
那个骑车放炸弹的人欠赌场钱
The guy on the bike, the bomber,
owed money to the casinos.
更重要的是，欠那些
经营赌场的人类的钱
More importantly,
to the humans who run them.
祖先们说让你活着
The ancestors told me
to let you live.
不管他们想要什么
我都会保证献给他们
Whatever it is they want,
I will make sure they get it.
他们要我们杀了克劳斯的孩子
They want us to kill Klaus' child.
我被下咒了
我不知道我还剩多长时间
I've been hexed,
and I don't know how long I have.
我打电话是要告诉你神父死了
KLAUS: I'm calling to let you know
the priest is dead.
你的驱逐暂停24小时
Your exile is suspended
for the next 24 hours.
你可以回法语区来埋葬你的朋友
You may return to the Quarter
to bury your friend.
你好啊
Hi.
好久不见，孩子
Greetings, boy.
片名：创始吸血鬼（第一季）
剧名：与橘同行
纽奥良充满着鬼魂
WOMAN:
New Orleans is full of ghosts.
那些死去的人总在这里徘徊
主演：约瑟夫摩根
Our dead are always here hovering.
当超自然生物死去后
主演：丹尼尔吉利斯
When supernatural creatures die,
他们注定永远孤独地
主演：丹尼尔吉利斯
they're doomed
to spend eternity alone
看着这个没有他们的世界继续运转
主演：菲比托金
watching the world go on
without them.
先祖女巫并不会如此
查尔斯麦可戴维斯
Of course, that's not the case
for the ancestral witches.
我们以另一种方式留在这世上
We linger in a different way.
与大地融为一体
主演：莉雅派普斯
Consecrated in the earth,
增强它的能量
replenishing its power.
那人类呢？
主演：丹妮儿坎贝尔
What about humans?
一些人得以安息
而另一些则不能
Some find peace.
Some don't.
我得出席神父的守夜仪式
I have to make an appearance
at the priest's wake.
你们三个回学校去
You three head back to the lycee.
花点时间想想那些
Take some time
to think about those spirits
可能仍在你身边徘徊的灵魂
who might still be walking
alongside you.
我不明白为什么我们要关心
基兰欧康诺的事
I don't know why we're supposed
to care about Kieran O'Connell.
因为当我们社区的一名
重要成员去世时，莫妮克
We care because when a pillar
of our community passes, Monique,
我们就该停火，向他致敬
you call a cease-fire
and pay respects.
或者你只是想去见克劳斯
你们俩最近走得很近啊
Or you just wanna see Klaus.
You two are getting cozy.
我需要米卡森家族的信任
这样我才能接近他们
I need the Mikaelsons to trust me
so I can get close enough--
去杀死那个孩子吗？
To kill their baby?
制片：克里斯多福贺利尔
(SlGHS)
去完成祖先交给我的使命
制片：兰斯安德森
To fulfill my obligation
to our ancestors.
回家去，莫妮克
Go home, Monique.
制片：邦妮怀斯
嘿，在想什么呢？
Hey, Earth to you.
- 你的脸…
- 会好的
-Your face....
-Will heal.
听着，我想谢谢你
Listen, I wanted to thank you.
那你不如帮我把酒倒满吧
Unless you come equipped
with the means to fill this,
其他的废话就不用说了
no additional platitudes
are necessary.
好吧
Okay.
编剧：卡丽娜艾德利麦肯齐
茱莉普烈克
我心情不好
I'm in a crap mood
是因为我叔叔刚去世
导演：西尔万怀特
because my uncle just died
而大家却像过狂欢节一样疯在作乐
导演：西尔万怀特
and people are partying
like it's Mardi Gras.
你的理由又是什么？
What's your excuse?
- 克劳斯，说真的，发生什么…
- 我最近常做梦
-Klaus, seriously, what's going--
-I've been having these dreams
梦见我死去的父亲
about my dead father.
这不用你诊断，亲爱的
我很清楚是为什么
No diagnosis necessary, love.
I've already got this one covered.
我害怕当一个父亲
My fears of fatherhood,
害怕自己会像我父亲那样
给我的孩子留下不可磨灭的阴影
of scarring my child
as my father scarred me,
这让我噩梦连连
are manifesting as nightmares.
这话还真是老套
It's horrifically cliche.
老实说，我很惊讶
Truthfully,
I'm just surprised to hear
你会主动承认你即将为人父
you acknowledge out loud
that you're going to be a dad.
你孩子的母亲这几个月来都住在河口
Your baby mama's been living
in the bayou for months.
这或许不是一个做父亲的该有的表现
It's not exactly What to Expect
When You're Expecting.
我比你想像中更了解
I know more about the trials
of fatherhood
做父亲的责任，卡蜜儿
than you might imagine, Camille.
那你之前还做得真不错呢
And it worked out so well for you
the first time.
你就继续这么做吧
Why change a thing?
你是来归还从我这偷走的财产吗？
Well, I see you've come
to return some stolen property.
恰恰相反
On the contrary.
我决定留下这个孩子
I've decided the boy
shall remain with me.
很遗憾，他不卖
Unfortunately, he's not for sale.
我并不想要买下他
Well, I do not wish to buy him.
- 我要你放他自由
- 如果我拒绝呢？
-You will grant him his freedom.
-And if I say no?
你似乎误解了，这并没有商量的余地
You seem to have misinterpreted
the matter as up for debate.
好吧，你带走就是了
Fine. Take him.
反正他对我来说一文不值
He wasn't worth a damn
to me anyway.
别人说他是你父亲
They told me he is your father.
是真的吗？
Is it true?
知道吗，我父亲也恨我
You know, my father hated me, too.
事实上，马赛勒斯
The truth is, Marcellus,
家人并不只是
family can be more
那些与你有血缘关系的人
than just those
with whom we share blood.
我们可以选择
We can choose.
我知道最近我很少在这附近出现
I know I haven't been around
these parts lately.
我想这正是基兰神父想看到的
It's a testament to Father Kieran
我们可以齐聚一堂
举杯共饮
that we could come together
and share a drink
分享故事
and a story or two.
25年前，基兰的父亲死后
Kieran rolled into town
on a rusty old cruiser
他开着一辆破旧的汽车来到了这里
after his daddy died
25 years ago.
说真的，这家伙可会玩了
And, damn it, that guy could party.
当然那是在他成为神父之前
That was, of course,
before he took his vows.
但就算那时，他也全心为法语区服务
But even then,
he was committed to the Quarter.
他知道这里需要他
He knew that this town needed him.
至今仍是
And we still do.
- 敬基神父
-MARCELLUS: To Father K.
-CROWD: To Father K.
看来我们想法一样
Looks like we had the same idea.
你叫卡蜜，对吧？
It's Cami, right?
有人告诉我基兰的项链不见了
I've been informed
that Kieran's necklace is missing
他一直戴着的那把钥匙
我想他是留给我的
and the key that he always wore.
I assume he left it for me.
你说什么？
Excuse me?
我太失礼了
我是佛朗西丝卡科雷亚
How rude of me.
I'm Francesca Correa.
我接管了你叔叔的职位
当人类决策群代表
I took over your uncle's position
as faction representative
当时他已经疯掉了
when his mental faculties
were compromised.
他没疯，他是被下咒的
His faculties weren't compromised.
He was hexed.
被我们的敌人下的咒
Hexed by one of our enemies.
听着，大家寄望我来保护
城里人类的安全
Look, I'm invested in protecting
the people of this city.
要做到的话，我需要那把钥匙
And to do that, I need the key.
一定是掉了
It must have fallen off
他最后死的时候可经历不少事情
during the events
that led to his untimely death.
真是不好意思
I'm so sorry.
看起来真野蛮
Seems rather uncivilized.
在深爱的人的尸体旁又笑又跳
To laugh and dance
around the body of a loved one.
总比你表达悲伤的方式
好多了，尼克劳斯
Yes. Far better to practice
your process of grief, Niklaus?
否认、愤怒，还在地下室囤积棺材
Denial, rage,
and hoarding coffins in basements.
我先提醒你，海莉
I will warn you, Hayley,
尼克劳斯今天心情不太好哦
Niklaus is in a spectacularly
foul mood today.
滚开
Sod off.
这些月光戒指到底是什么回事？
What's the deal
with these moonlight rings?
奥利佛每五秒钟就想闹一次革命
Oliver's trying to start
a revolution every five seconds.
大家都变得很害怕，很生气
而且老实说，我不想再忍了
People are scared, angry.
And, frankly, I'm tired of stalling.
今天是和平的日子，海莉
你就好好享受吧
It's a day of peace, Hayley.
Try and enjoy it.
同时，还有许多形形色色的未知敌人
And in the meantime
with all manner of unknown enemies
正密谋对付我们家族
conspiring against our family,
- 你必须搬回来和我们一起住
- 好极了
-you'll move back in with us.
-Awesome.
然后我们又会干那些事了
你把我关进象牙塔
Then we can do that thing
where you lock me in the tower,
我逃跑，搞出一场闹剧
I escape, there's drama,
然后你们俩都意识到
and then you two both realize
that I'm very capable
我很会照顾自己
of looking after myself.
戒指的事正在进行中
我说到做到
The rings are in progress.
I will live up to my word.
我们会找到并惩罚
We will find and punish
在河口攻击你们的人
whoever launched the attack
on the bayou.
为了你的自身安全，你必须回来
And you will return to the compound
for your own safety.
但现在
我要喝完这瓶酒
But right now,
I'm gonna finish this bottle.
然后心怀希望
And the next
in the hopes of drowning
能把今天来纠缠我的魔鬼干掉
the demon that has chosen today
to haunt me.
干杯吧，麦可
向梦中的完美时刻致敬
Cheers, Mikael.
Impeccable Freudian timing.
说详细些
Elaborate.
你是不是梦到我们父亲了？
Have you dreamt of our father?
来啊
尽情嘲笑我吧
Go ahead.
Have a good laugh.
我敢确信，我并不觉得这件事
I can assure you
there isn't a piece of this
有一丁点好笑的地方，尼克劳斯
that I find even remotely amusing,
Niklaus,
尤其是我最近也经常梦到他
especially considering
I've been dreaming of him too.
什么？
What?
如果你也梦到他了
If you are also seeing him....
也许我们那些难捉摸的未知敌人
Perhaps our elusive,
unknown enemy
正在精心策划进一步攻击
is orchestrating a further attack.
那么想打断和平日，还有什么方法
Well then, what better way
to punctuate a day of peace,
比杀人更好呢？
than by killing someone?
你从派对上过来啦
You disappeared from the party.
你能不能解释一下
Would you care to explain
为什么你要让我们梦到父亲
来折磨我们？
why you would choose to torment us
with visions of our father?
你们的父亲？
Your father?
我没有啊，我不会干这种事
Oh, I didn't. I wouldn't.
是啊，我真笨
一定是另一个女巫
Of course. How foolish of me.
It must have been that other witch
穿着蕾丝睡衣在我们房子里走来走去
that's been parading throughout
our house in scraps of lace.
我知道你嘴巴很会说话，洁妮薇
I know how talented you are
with your tongue, Genevieve.
我劝你还是用你的嘴巴来回答问题
Might I recommend you use it
to provide answers?
不然我真是不舍得撕烂它
I would so hate to tear it
from your mouth.
虽然我很享受
As much as I enjoy
你们三番两次指控我做了某件坏事
these repeated accusations
of wrongdoings,
但这次我真不知道你们在说什么
I don't know
what you're talking about.
但如果你们俩都梦到你们死去的父亲
But if you've both been seeing
your dead father,
我可以试试帮你们找到答案
I can try to get you answers.
那好，去找吧
Fine. Go.
- 尼克劳斯，你休想…
- 去
-Niklaus, don't you dare--
-Go.
你不相信她
你做得对
You don't trust her.
And you're right not to.
只有傻子才会相信她
Only a fool would
但她一定希望我们相信她，不是吗？
but she certainly wants us to,
doesn't she?
让我猜猜，这事一定
Let me guess.
There's something of benefit for you
对你有什么好处，对吗？
in all of this, isn't there?
我需要一个女巫来为狼人做戒指
I need a witch to make those rings
for the wolves.
也许答案和合作，两者我们都能得到
And perhaps we'll get both answers
and cooperation.
我不知道祖先们
I don't know if the ancestors
would like us
是否会喜欢我们扰乱灵魂世界
messing around in the spirit world.
只是个简单的降神会而已
It's just a simple seance.
假女巫会用降神会来吸引游客
Phony witches do seances
to impress tourists.
那都是假的
They're not real.
- 这是干嘛的？
- 这是我朋友提姆的
-WOMAN: What's that for?
-DAVlNA: It was my friend Tim's.
来吧，如果我们不能对这种东西施魔法
Come on.
What's the point of being a witch
我们当女巫还有什么意义？
if we can't use our magic
for stuff like this?
提姆？
Tim?
多么美妙的旋律
What a delightful tune.
克劳斯允许你在法语区待24小时
(DRlNK BElNG POURED)
So Klaus gives you 24 hours
in the Quarter
而你却在这里跟我一起守灵吗？
and you're spending it
coffin-sitting with me?
不为战争做准备，不进行安排吗？
No preparations for war?
No chess pieces to move?
我们在纪念基兰
We're honoring Kieran.
就算是我们这些坏人也可以休息一晚
Even us bad guys
can take the night off.
或许你可以
Maybe you can.
但我不确定人类是不是表现良好
Not sure the humans
are on their best behavior.
稍早有个叫佛朗西丝卡的人
This Francesca person
cornered me earlier,
逼问我什么钥匙的事
asking about some key.
- 你怎么跟她说的？
- 这不重要，钥匙不在我手上
What'd you tell her?
It doesn't matter.
I don't have it.
但你知道
不然你就会问“什么钥匙？"
But you know
or you would have asked, what key?
我叫小约帮我偷来的
I had Josh lift it for me.
从我病得快死的叔叔身上偷的吗？
Off my uncle's sick
and dying body?
我是想帮你一个忙
I'm trying to do you a favor.
相信我，你不想卷进这事的
Trust me, you don't wanna be a part
of any of this.
相信你？你开什么玩笑？
Trust you?
Are you kidding me?
卡蜜，这事你控制不了
Cami, this is bigger than you.
别小看我，马赛尔
你知道什么事我控制不了吗？
Don't patronize me, Marcel.
Do you know what's bigger than me?
我叔叔疯了
把我打个半死
My uncle lost his mind,
beat the crap out of me,
然后死了
and then died.
现在我得整夜守着他的遗体
And now,
I have to sit by his body all night.
我跟你一起守
I'll sit with you.
我不是想对你撒谎
我是想保护你
I'm not trying to lie to you.
I'm trying to protect you.
你现在马上走
You need to leave, like, now.
- 我会告诉你钥匙的事
- 我不想知道
-I will tell you about the key.
-I don't wanna know!
我什么都不想知道
I don't wanna know any of it.
洁妮薇
Genevieve.
我问过了，并不只有你父亲这样
I asked around.
It's not just your father.
困住超自然灵魂的炼狱
The purgatory,
正在瓦解
where supernatural souls
are trapped, is disintegrating.
你说瓦解是什么意思？
What do you mean, "disintegrating"?
她说得对，差不多吧
事实上是爆炸崩溃了
She's right, more or less.
It's actually imploding.
我打给了一个迷瀑镇的班奈女巫
虽然很不情愿
I made a call to a rather reluctant
Bennett witch in Mystic Falls,
她也这么说
who said the same thing.
死去的人被卷进虚无里了
The dead are being torn away
into nothingness.
但他们可不想就这么无声地走掉
And they're not interested
in going quietly.
你是说我们的父亲
虽然即将永远消失
So you're saying that our father,
faced with permanent extinction,
但他决定用剩下的时间折磨我们
has decided to spend
his remaining time tormenting us.
真令人愉悦啊
How delightful.
往好处想
Well, on the plus side,
我们很快就能永远摆脱
他那可恨的灵魂了
we'll soon be rid
of his abhorrent soul forever.
那是多好的事啊
And what a good riddance
that will be.
这么说没我事了吧，以利亚？
So, am I in the clear, Elijah?
还是说你们俩
Or is there a new conspiracy
有新的阴谋要威胁我？
you two would like
to threaten me over?
目前还没想到什么
Nothing springs to mind
at this precise moment.
是吗？谢谢了
Oh, gee, thanks.
我得回到女孩们身边去了
I have to get back to the girls.
或许明天葬礼过后
Perhaps tomorrow after the funeral,
我们可以小聚一下
you and I could spend
some time together.
就你和我
Alone.
再看看吧
I suppose we'll have to see.
拜托告诉我你除了欲擒故纵外
Please tell me you've designed
a stronger method
还有更好的办法控制这女巫
to control the witch
than playing hard to get.
我一直都偏爱传统
Well, I've always been partial
to the classics.
海莉，是吧？
Hayley, right?
我猜你到这来不是来交新朋友的
I'm guessing you're not here
because you wanna make a new friend.
我不把恐怖份子当朋友
I don't count terrorists as friends.
从窃盗到勒索我都被指控过
Wow. I've been accused of everything
from grand larceny to blackmail.
但恐怖份子还是头一遭呢
But terrorist, that's new.
一个人类骑摩托车到我们河口的家
A human pulled up to our home
in the bayou on a motorcycle
然后把自己炸了
and blew himself up.
我听说了，真可怕
I heard. Awful.
晚安
Good night.
传言说
Word on the street is
他欠了皇宫赌场十万元
he owed 100 grand
to the Palace Royale Casino.
在他死后，债务也一笔勾销了
And then after he died,
the debt was erased.
就像变魔术一样
Just like magic.
杰夫是我轮盘赌桌上的常客
Jeff was a fixture
at my roulette table.
他的运气时好时坏
Sometimes he was up.
Sometimes he was down.
我不向他的家人追究债款
I absolved his family
of the debt he owed
是出于好心
out of the goodness of my heart.
随便查吧
Feel free to sniff around.
跟我没关系
My hands are clean.
我建议你注意一下礼节
And I'd advise you
to mind your manners.
你还活着该觉得庆幸了
It's lucky you're still alive.
狼人们都在窃窃私语你的事
皇室什么的
You're the one the wolves
all whisper about, like royalty.
如果我想伤害狼人
If I was interested
in hurting the wolves,
你就会是我的目标
you'd be my target.
我想干掉某人的时候
绝不会失手
And when I go after someone,
I don't miss.
你的发言真优美
Your reading was beautiful.
偷偷摸摸靠近不公平，我还在生气
Sneak attack. Not fair.
I'm still pissed.
跟我说说钥匙的事
Tell me about the key.
你不是说你不想知道吗？
I thought you said
you didn't wanna know.
我想说我没管它就睡了
但我根本没睡
I'd like to say I slept on it
but I didn't sleep.
我一整晚没睡守着被下咒的神父尸体
I stayed awake all night
next to the body of a hexed priest
只为了参加一场满是吸血鬼的葬礼
only to attend a funeral
filled with vampires.
所以我在想
你该告诉我那把钥匙的事
So I'm thinking
you should tell me about the key.
基兰告诉我那把钥匙能开放
Kieran told me that the key leads
对付超自然生物的东西
to something that can be used
against the supernaturals
如果我们做得太过分的话
if we ever get too far out of line.
我和基兰的关系 有过起伏
但我们信任彼此
Kieran and I had our ups and downs
but we trusted each other.
所以我也没管
So I let it be.
因为我知道他一旦想用钥匙
Because I knew if he had to use
打开什么潘朵拉盒子
whatever Pandora's box
that key opens,
一定是他别无选择了
it'd be because
he didn't have a choice.
你大可开口跟我要啊
You could've just asked me for it.
那你就会给我吗？
Would you have just handed it over?
- 钥匙能打开什么？
- 我不知道
-So, what does it open?
-I don't know.
我昨晚把全城翻遍了去找它
I turned the city upside down
last night trying to find it.
教堂、神父的房子
连你家族的坟墓都找了
The church, the rectory.
I even searched your family's tomb.
这就好比大海捞针一样困难
It's hard to find a needle
in a haystack
而我连针长什么样都不知道
when you don't even know
what the needle looks like.
而你想看看我是否知道
And you want to know
if I have any ideas.
所以你才来
That's why you're here.
我来是因为我朋友死了
而另一个朋友在伤心
I'm here because my friend died
and my other friend is grieving.
你尽管怀疑我的动机，卡蜜
You can question my intentions
all day long, Cami.
但我是为基兰而来的
为你而来
I'm here for Kieran.
And I'm here for you.
你还好吗？你看起来…
You all right? You look--
像挺了好几年的大肚子那样
愤世嫉俗吗？
A hundred months' pregnant
and pissed off at the world?
我是要说“你看起来很美”
I was going to say, you look lovely.
你觉得那些爆炸是冲着我来的吗？
Do you think I was the target
of those bombings?
当然是
KLAUS:
Of course you were the target.
如果我要对狼人开战
那一定从你下手
Were I to wage a war on the wolves,
you'd be my first kill.
我会把你高悬示众，供你的崇拜者观赏
I would string you up
for all your worshipers to see.
我想我弟弟的意思是
I believe that was my brother's way
of telling you
他希望你和我们一起回家
he'd like you
to return home with us.
或许可以换种说法，尼克劳斯
Perhaps try a different approach,
Niklaus,
少提点打打杀杀的
with fewer references to murder.
尽管我很不想把你扛在肩膀上
As much as I would hate
to throw you over my shoulder
把又踢又喊的你一路拖回去
and drag you kicking and screaming
to the compound,
但我们都清楚，为了我的孩子
我会这么做
we both know I will
for the sake of my child.
一个噩梦
One bad dream,
就突然让你有了为人父的责任心了
and suddenly you wanna be
a responsible daddy.
让我把道理跟你讲清楚
Let me put this in perspective.
我父亲生前一直折磨我
My father lived to torment me.
我不想成为第二个他
It is not my intention
to become him.
我不会让我孩子承受这种苦难
This cycle of misery ends
with my child.
你在为自己办解的同时忘了一件事
You forgot one thing
in your attempt to plead your case.
她不是你的孩子，是我们的
She's not your child.
She's ours.
- 发自肺腑啊，尼克劳斯
- 我真讨厌葬礼
-Very heartfelt, Niklaus.
-I bloody hate funerals.
- 卡蜜
- 海莉，嗨
Cami.
Hayley, hi.
嗨，我知道你不认识我
Hi. I know you don't know me.
我只是想说
我对你叔叔的离去表示遗憾
I just wanted to say that l--
I'm sorry about your uncle.
他在泥乱时期非常照顾像我这样的人
He was really good to people like me
during the storm,
我很感激
and I really appreciated that.
谢谢
Thank you.
你另有目的，对吧？
You want something, don't you?
我知道现在不是时候
I'm sorry about the timing.
我只是想知道，在他去世之前
I was just wondering
if before he died,
有没有提到过佛朗西丝卡科雷亚
he said anything weird
about Francesca Correa.
我想她可能和河口
I think that
she may have been involved
那起攻击有关
in an attack on the bayou.
如果你听说什么…
If you hear anything--
听着，海莉
我尽力不牵扯进这些事
Look, Hayley, I'm trying,
mostly failing,
虽然大都失败了
to stay out of all this stuff
但她是个十足的贱人
but she's a real bitch.
所以没问题，如果我听到什么
一定会告诉你
So, yeah, if I hear anything,
I'll let you know.
谢了，再次对你叔叔的离去表示遗憾
Thanks.
Again, sorry about your uncle.
我也是
Me too.
克劳斯
Klaus!
海莉
KLAUS: Hayley.
- 让我来
- 别碰她
-GENEVlEVE: I can help.
-ELlJAH: Don't you touch her.
让她来，以利亚
她当过护士
Let her be, Elijah.
She was a nurse.
我可以施一个咒
克劳斯，从食品柜拿点洋甘菊来
There's a spell I can do. Klaus,
get chamomile from the pantry.
她在发
你的外套，以利亚
She's trembling.
Your jacket, Elijah.
她没呼吸了
She's not breathing.
我能听到孩子的心跳，但听不到她的
I can hear the baby's heartbeat
but not hers.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我想…
我是你的家人
I suppose I'm family.
太初有道
道与神同在
In the beginning was the word.
And the word was with God.
这道太初与神同在
生命在他里头
He was with God in the beginning.
In him was life.
这生命就是人的光
And that life was the light
of all mankind.
光照在黑暗里
The light shines
in the darkness.
黑暗却不接受光
And the darkness
has not overcome it.
卡蜜
Cami.
我们没为西恩举办葬礼
Sean didn't have a funeral.
我父母不想跟他有任何瓜葛
Our parents wanted nothing
to do with him,
所以市政府就把他跟那些罪犯
so the city had him buried out here
还有无名氏葬在了一起
with the criminals
and the John Does.
都是没人爱的人
The great unloved.
你说你来看过我们家族的墓
You said you checked
my family's tomb
但我一直在想
but I've been thinking.
一直以来，我不知道
All this time, I wondered
为什么基兰不把西恩
why Kieran
didn't have Sean interred
和他的家人葬在一起
where he belonged, with the family.
但我突然意识到
But then I realized,
会不会是他找到了机会
what if he saw an opportunity
将他不想被人发现的东西藏起来？
to hide something he didn't want
anyone else to find?
卡蜜，我们改天再说吧
Cami, we can do this another time.
正因为今天不是时候
Bad timing is the theme of the day.
（西恩欧康诺
光照在黑暗里，黑暗却不接受光）
我需要一把大槌
I'm going to need a sledgehammer.
醒醒
Come on.
她还是没有呼吸
没用
She's still not breathing.
It's not working.
看来我已经声名远播了
I assume my reputation precedes me.
这是噩梦，我在做梦
This is a nightmare.
I'm dreaming.
恰恰相反，亲爱的
这一切非常真实
On the contrary, my darling.
This is very real.
欢迎来到我的地狱
(GASPS)
Welcome to my hell.
永远困在这里
Stuck in an eternity
看着那个恐怖的生物
of watching over
that hideous creature
我的孩子还叫他兄弟
my children call brother.
你已经死了
我怎么会在这里？
You're dead.
How can I be here?
我的天啊
不，不
Oh, my God.
No! No!
- 孩子
- 孩子？
-The baby.
-The baby?
那孩子从来就不该活着
That kid never had a chance.
你是嫌你的血统还不够肮脏
And as if your bloodline
isn't filth enough,
要用克劳斯的血来污染一下吗？
you poison it
by merging it with Klaus'?
那个杀不死的畜牲还妄想做爸爸
The deathless vermin
fancying himself a daddy.
她没死，我也没死
She's not dead.
I'm not dead.
如果我死了，你就不用费力杀我了
If I was dead,
you wouldn't be trying to kill me.
我要带她去找真正的医生
I'm taking her to a real doctor.
如果你动她，我的咒语就会失效
If you move her from here,
my spell will break.
没有足够的时间送她去医院了
There won't be enough time
to get her to a hospital.
如果现在取出孩子，孩子会没事吗？
Will the baby survive
if delivered now?
- 我自己把她抓出来就行
- 那样海莉会失血而死
-I'll rip it out of her myself.
-Hayley will bleed to death.
- 我不能失去孩子
- 谁都不能失去
-I won't lose that baby.
-I won't lose either of them.
我知道该怎么做
去拿我的包包，符咒袋，快点
I know what to do. Get my bag.
The gris-gris pouch. Now!
你已经死了，麦可
你的儿子打败了你
You're dead, Mikael.
Your son already beat you.
他不是我儿子
He is not my son!
他是个祸害
一个彻头彻尾的孬种
He's a scourge,
a walking symbol of weakness!
你肚子里的那个孽种没救的
There is no saving that atrocity
festering in your womb.
总有一天克劳斯会毁掉它
Klaus will destroy it
one way or another.
不如现在就让它死，你也一同作陪
Better he dies now
and you along with it.
我女儿比克劳斯幸运多了
My daughter has an advantage
Klaus never had.
她永远，永远都不会认识你
She will never, ever know you.
海莉
Hayley.
你没事，亲爱的，你没事了
You're all right, love.
You're all right.
我见到他了，他想杀我
I saw him, and he tried to kill me.
我见到麦可了
I saw Mikael.
你的生命力还真强啊，小狼
You've proved quite resilient,
little wolf.
你们两个都是战士
Fighters, both of you.
我们别无选择，特别是最近
I guess we've had to be,
especially lately.
我决定要搬回来
I've decided
that I'm going to move back in.
可算让我松了口气
Well, I'm relieved to hear it.
但别派人监视我
也别对我下指导棋
But no mouth-breathing bodyguards,
no telling me what to do.
我只要求孩子安全
All I ask
is that the child is kept safe.
那我的安全呢？
她出生以后呢？
And what about me?
What happens after she's born?
你要是想把她从我身边抢走，我…
If you try to take her away from me,
l--
跟我来，好吗？
Come with me, hmm?
来吧，我有东西要给你看
Please.
I want to show you something.
不管你信不信，海莉
Believe it or not, Hayley,
其实我很希望你留在这里
I would actually like you
to be here.
我们的女儿应该由父母共同养大
在自己的家成长
Our daughter should be raised
by her parents in her family home.
你、我、以利亚和这个奇迹般的孩子
You, me, Elijah,
and the miracle baby
生活在一个屋檐下
all under one roof.
听起来像是个糟糕的实境秀
Sounds like a bad reality show.
你说你见到了我父亲
You said you saw my father.
你为什么要叫他父亲？
他不是你的亲生父亲
Why do you call him that?
He's not your real dad.
他所造成的伤害只有父亲能做到
He's done damage
only a father could do.
他跟你说什么了？
What did he say to you?
都是胡说
Nothing true.
海莉和孩子都没事
Hayley and the baby are fine.
等她休息好了，我可以带她去看医生
I'd take her to a doctor
when she's gotten some rest,
如果你想的话，不过她没事了
if you want,
but she's in the clear.
我自己出去吧
I'll see myself out.
洁妮薇
Genevieve.
多谢你的帮忙
Thank you for your help.
不客气
You're welcome.
你把我妹妹与家人分开
You tore my sister from my family.
我无法原谅你这一点
I cannot forgive that.
不过，我决定对你仁慈一点
However, I may be inclined
to show a degree more kindness
只要你答应帮我一个小忙
if you were to help me
with a slight...issue.
- 请说
- 孩子出生后
-Anything--
-When the baby arrives,
海莉在月圆时又会开始变身
Hayley will once again transform
with a full moon.
我想为她做一份礼物
Now, I would like to create
for her a gift,
一枚带有魔力的戒指
可以阻止这个诅咒的戒指
a ring of empowerment,
something to control this curse.
什么样的咒语能够…
What kind of spell would--?
我母亲的咒语可以
在她的魔法书里有
A spell of my mother's,
from her grimoire.
据我所知
你非常渴望那本魔法书
Which, as I understand,
you've been rather eager to obtain.
一定是有人先拿走了
Someone must have gotten to it.
应该不是
I don't think so.
我哥哥15年前教过我这个密码
My brother taught me this code
15 years ago.
我不知道他怎么学会的
I never knew how he learned it.
- 你能告诉我什么意思吗？
- 我可以
-You can tell me what that says?
-I can.
但我不会说的，抱歉
But I won't. I'm sorry.
- 卡蜜，你这样太…
- 危险，我知道
-Cami, this is too--
-Dangerous. Yeah. I got it.
但如果是基兰教了西恩这个
But if Kieran taught Sean this,
我哥哥早就注定要卷入这一切
my brother was meant
to be brought into it all along.
现在这是我的责任了
That makes it
my responsibility now,
不管我乐不乐意
whether I like it or not.
你到底对海莉做了什么？
What the hell did you do to Hayley?
我只是做祖先们要求的事
I was trying to do
what the ancestors asked.
那个孩子也有女巫的血统
That baby is part witch.
祖先们想把她献祭给大地
The ancestors want her consecrated
to the earth
这样她的魔法就能为我们提供能量
so her magic can fuel our community.
她必须先出生然后再死
She has to be born first
before she can die.
滚
我不想看到你
Leave.
I don't wanna look at you.
别逼我这么做
她只是个孩子
Don't make me do this.
She's a baby.
别让我变成残忍的人
Don't make me a monster.
求求你
Please.
不
No.
不，不
No. No.
对不起，对不起
对不起，我会做的
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'll do it.
你想要什么我都会做的
I'll do whatever you want.
海莉同意回来和我们一起住了
Hayley has agreed
to return home to us.
自愿的
Of her own freewill.
麦可真的消失后
你觉得我能找到安宁吗？
When Mikael is truly gone,
do you think then I'll find peace?
我当然希望如此
I certainly hope so.
尽管让你困扰的不只我们父亲
尼克劳斯
Although it's not only our father
that haunts you, Niklaus.
你也许会想和生者言归于好
You might want to make peace
with the living.
我要知道为什么他们还不能自由
I demand to know why their freedom
has not been granted.
当权者都支持让他们自由了
All necessary authorities
have ruled in their favor.
你以为我不记得你吗，小子？
You think I don't remember you, boy?
他们把你变成他们的一员了吗？
Have they turned you
into one of them yet?
我想是没有
I thought not.
- 来，让我治愈你
- 不
-Here. Let me heal you.
-No.
你总是说我们可以选择自己的家人
You've always said
we choose our family.
我对你来说是什么，克劳斯？
So, what am I to you, Klaus?
你用匕首封住你妹妹时对我许下承诺
You made me a promise
when you daggered your sister.
现在终于是做选择的时候了
It's finally time to make a choice.
现在转变我吧
或者就让我死去
Turn me now.
Or let me die.
你不知道你在要求我做什么
You do not know
what you ask of me.
变得和我一样
Becoming like me.
会夺走你所有善良的一面
It would rob you of all
that makes you good.
我知道你是什么
你是什么样的人
I know what you are.
Who you are.
这就是我想要的
This is what I want.
求求你
Please.
钟响时你的假期就结束了
Your furlough ends
when the clock strikes.
我知道，别担心
I'm aware. Don't worry.
那时我就会离这里远远的了
I intend to be far away from here
by then.
但我只是在河对岸
But just because
I'm across the river
不代表我就玩完了
doesn't mean
I'm out of the game.
月圆之日就要来了
A full moon's coming.
我知道你和狼人计划着什么
I know you're up to something
with the wolves.
我绞尽脑汁想要猜出是什么
And I've been racking my brain,
trying to figure out what.
不管我怎么想
结局都是我和我的人会死
And any way I do the math,
it ends with me and my guys dead.
或许我们该站成一排
Or maybe we're supposed
to fall in line,
再一次宣誓效忠于你
pledge our allegiance to you
all over again.
那么如果我们被咬了
你也许会屈尊治愈我们
So if we get bitten,
you might deign to cure us.
这就是你的目的吗？
Is that what you're after?
想都别想
Because it's not gonna happen.
那是你的选择
Well, that will be your choice,
正如你选择把我父亲带到这里
just as you chose
to bring my father to town.
你比任何人都了解
You, who knows better than anyone
被父亲憎恶的痛苦
the specific agony
of a father's hatred.
- 克劳斯
- 我花了数十年
-Klaus--
-I spent decades
试图弥补你父亲所做的一切
trying to make up
for what your father did.
我是怎么让你失望的？
How did I fail?
也许是伤得太深了
Maybe the scars
just ran too deep.
晚安，马赛勒斯
Good night, Marcellus.
你没让我失望
You didn't fail me.
你养育了我
You raised me.
你教会了我一切
You taught me everything
that I know.
你教会我
我不能够软弱
You taught me
that I can't afford to be weak,
特别是在我的敌人更加强大的时候
not when my enemies are stronger.
所以不管你和狼人在密谋着什么
So, whatever it is
you got coming with the wolves,
你要知道，我会为了我的人奋战
just know
that I'm gonna fight for my guys.
我会为了我的城市奋战
我会一直奋战到最后一刻
I'm gonna fight for my city.
And I will fight until I am dead.
我想你也会这么做的
I would expect nothing less.
如果我死了，而有人办派对庆祝
我会气疯的
If I died and someone threw a party,
I would be so pissed.
你差点就死了
You almost did.
一千年来，我想不起哪一次
In a thousand years,
I can't recall a time
有这么害怕过
I've felt so...frightened.
以利亚
Elijah.
提姆，是你吗？
Tim, is that you?
你是谁？
Who are you?
你朋友提摩西已经往前走了，黛维娜
Your friend Timothy
has moved on, Davina.
我真的很抱歉我儿子对他做的事
I'm truly sorry
for what my son did to him.
你是克劳斯的父亲
You're Klaus' father.
我是唯一一个能让你永远摆脱他的人
And I'm the only one
who can rid you of him forever.
但首先，我的小女巫
我需要你
But first, my little witch,
I need you.
我能做什么？
What can I do?
你能让我复活
You can bring me back to life.
片名：创始吸血鬼（第一季）